<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="dia_whatmeansdia">What is true about DIA?</string>
    <string name="dia_label_exam">Duration of Insulin Action (DIA)</string>
    <string name="dia_profile">You should set the value for DIA in your profile.</string>
    <string name="dia_minimumis5h">The minimum allowed value is 5 hours.</string>
    <string name="dia_hint1">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/SettingUpAaps/YourAapsProfile.html</string>
    <string name="dia_meaningisequaltodiapump">If you are satisfied that the value for DIA that you used in your pump before AAPS worked well, there is no need to change this when you start looping.</string>
    <string name="dia_valuemustbedetermined">You should determine for yourself the appropriate value for DIA.</string>
    <string name="hypott_label">Hypo Temp-Target</string>
    <string name="hypott_whenhypott">What is the primary reason to set a hypo temp target?</string>
    <string name="hypott_wrongbasal">To correct for hypos caused by incorrect basal rate settings.</string>
    <string name="hypott_preventoversmb">To prevent AAPS from overcorrecting for a blood glucose rise caused by the fast-acting carbs used to treat a hypo.</string>
    <string name="hypott_exercise">To correct for a hypo induced as a result of exercise.</string>
    <string name="hypott_0basal">To prevent blood glucose from going low if there is already a 0% temporary basal rate running.</string>
    <string name="hypott_hint1">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/DailyLifeWithAaps/TempTargets.html</string>
    <string name="pumpdisconnect_label">Reasons for applying "Disconnect pump" in AAPS</string>
    <string name="pumpdisconnect_unnecessary">This is unnecessary as insulin will not be delivered if the pump is physically disconnected.</string>
    <string name="pumpdisconnect_missinginsulin">It prevents AAPS from accounting for insulin that was not delivered whilst the pump is physically disconnected.</string>
    <string name="pumpdisconnect_notstop">It will not stop insulin delivery if the pump remains connected to your body.</string>
    <string name="pumpdisconnect_openloop">It will send AAPS into open loop mode.</string>
    <string name="pumpdisconnect_hint1">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/DailyLifeWithAaps/AapsScreens.html#loop-status</string>
    <string name="objectives_label">AAPS Settings</string>
    <string name="objectives2_label">AAPS Settings</string>
    <string name="objectives_howtosave">What are the best practices for backing up your settings?</string>
    <string name="objectives_notesettings">You do not need to export your settings provided that you make a note of them.</string>
    <string name="objectives_afterobjective">Export your settings after you finish completing an objective.</string>
    <string name="objectives_afterchange">Export your settings after changing any of your settings.</string>
    <string name="objectives_afterinitialsetup">Export your settings after you finish your initial set-up and have set your Preferences.</string>
    <string name="objectives2_maintenance">Export your settings locally using the maintenance menu.</string>
    <string name="objectives2_internalstorage">Your settings file is found in the folder Internal Storage/AAPS/preferences on your phone.</string>
    <string name="objectives2_cloud">Copy your preferences file to a safe location outside of your phone (e.g. by using a cloud drive, connecting a cable to a computer, email, etc.)</string>
    <string name="objectives2_easyrestore">If your phone is damaged or lost, there are easy ways to remotely recover your settings without a backup.</string>
    <string name="objectives_hint1">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/Maintenance/ExportImportSettings.html</string>
    <string name="objectives_hint2">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/UsefulLinks/FAQ.html#what-emergency-equipment-is-recommended-to-take-with-me</string>
    <string name="noisycgm_label">Noisy CGM Readings</string>
    <string name="noisycgm_whattodo">What should be done if CGM data is noisy?</string>
    <string name="noisycgm_nothing">Do nothing - AAPS will deal with it.</string>
    <string name="noisycgm_pause">Disable the closed loop to avoid possible over or underdosing.</string>
    <string name="noisycgm_replacesensor">Replace consistently noisy or inaccurate sensors.</string>
    <string name="noisycgm_checksmoothing">Verify that your CGM app provides smoothed data.</string>
    <string name="noisycgm_hint1">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/CompatibleCgms/SmoothingBloodGlucoseData.html</string>
    <string name="exerciseprofile_label">Exercise and Profiles</string>
    <string name="exerciseprofile_whattodo">How can you use profiles to best help the system deal with aerobic exercise?</string>
    <string name="exerciseprofile_switchprofilebelow100">Do a profile switch to less than 100%.</string>
    <string name="exerciseprofile_switchprofileabove100">Do a profile switch to more than 100%.</string>
    <string name="exerciseprofile_leaveat100">Leave the profile set to 100%.</string>
    <string name="exerciseprofile_suspendloop">Suspend the loop.</string>
    <string name="exerciseprofile_hint1">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/DailyLifeWithAaps/TempTargets.html</string>
    <string name="exercise_label">Exercise and Temporary Targets</string>
    <string name="exercise_whattodo">How can you use temporary targets to best help the system deal with aerobic exercise?</string>
    <string name="exercise_settt">Set an activity blood glucose target starting a suitable time before beginning exercise.</string>
    <string name="exercise_setfinished">Set an activity blood glucose target after finishing exercise.</string>
    <string name="exercise_setunchanged">Leave your blood glucose target unchanged.</string>
    <string name="exercise_15g">Wait until blood glucose drops below your hypo temp target and then eat 15 g of fast acting carbohydrates.</string>
    <string name="exercise_hint1">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/DailyLifeWithAaps/TempTargets.html</string>
    <string name="basaltest_label">Basal, ISF, and I:C Testing</string>
    <string name="basaltest_when">When should these values be validated?</string>
    <string name="basaltest_beforeloop">Before starting looping.</string>
    <string name="basaltest_havingregularhighlow">When experiencing frequent high or low blood glucose.</string>
    <string name="basaltest_weekly">At least once per week.</string>
    <string name="basaltest_fixed">Once set and validated, these values should not change over time.</string>
    <string name="basaltest_hint1">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/SettingUpAaps/YourAapsProfile.html</string>
    <string name="prerequisites_label">Prerequisites</string>
    <string name="prerequisites_what">What is essential to set up and use AAPS?</string>
    <string name="prerequisites_build">A way to build AAPS. Either via a browser or a computer with Android Studio installed.</string>
    <string name="prerequisites_pump">A compatible insulin pump if you are planning to run a closed loop.</string>
    <string name="prerequisites_nightscout">Nightscout, to keep a log of all data and review settings.</string>
    <string name="prerequisites_beanandroiddeveloper">Experience in programming or editing code.</string>
    <string name="prerequisites_hint1">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/Getting-Started/ComponentOverview.html</string>
    <string name="prerequisites2_label">Prerequisites</string>
    <string name="prerequisites2_what">What is essential to set up and use AAPS?</string>
    <string name="prerequisites2_profile">Validated information to set up a profile (ISF, I:C ratio, basal rates, DIA etc.).</string>
    <string name="prerequisites2_device">A compatible Android device (e.g. mobile/cell phone, full Android watch, or tablet).</string>
    <string name="prerequisites2_internet">AAPS requires an internet connection to run in the closed loop.</string>
    <string name="prerequisites2_supportedcgm">A supported CGM and appropriate app to receive blood glucose values on the phone/device.</string>
    <string name="prerequisites2_hint1">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/Getting-Started/ComponentOverview.html</string>
    <string name="update_label">Updating AAPS</string>
    <string name="update_git">You need to have Git installed and configured on your computer.</string>
    <string name="update_asap">When updated versions of AAPS are released, the earlier versions may be remotely limited after a specified time.</string>
    <string name="update_keys">You should save and note the location of your keystore and use the same signing key for updates as for your previous installation.</string>
    <string name="update_askfriend">If you have difficulty building the apk, you can install an apk that has been built by a friend.</string>
    <string name="update_hint1">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/Maintenance/UpdateToNewVersion.html</string>
    <string name="troubleshooting_label">Troubleshooting</string>
    <string name="troubleshooting_wheretoask">Where can you look for help with AAPS?</string>
    <string name="troubleshooting_fb">You can ask for advice in the AAPS Users Facebook group.</string>
    <string name="troubleshooting_wiki">You should read (and re-read) the AAPS documentation.</string>
    <string name="troubleshooting_discord">You can ask for advice, discuss technical problems and feature requests in the AAPS Discord.</string>
    <string name="troubleshooting_github">You can submit issues such as bugs and feature requests at Github.</string>
    <string name="troubleshooting_yourendo">You should ask your diabetes clinic/endocrinologist.</string>
    <string name="troubleshooting_hint1">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/GettingHelp/WhereCanIGetHelp.html</string>
    <string name="troubleshooting_hint2">https://www.facebook.com/groups/AndroidAPSUsers/</string>
    <string name="troubleshooting_hint3">https://discord.gg/4fQUWHZ4Mw</string>
    <string name="troubleshooting_hint4">https://github.com/nightscout/AndroidAPS/issues</string>
    <string name="insulin_plugins">Insulin Plugins</string>
    <string name="insulin_ultrarapid">Which insulin should you use with the Ultra-Rapid Oref plugin?</string>
    <string name="insulin_fiasp">Fiasp®</string>
    <string name="insulin_novorapid">NovoRapid®/Novolog®</string>
    <string name="insulin_humalog">Humalog®</string>
    <string name="insulin_actrapid">Actrapid®/Humulin R®/"regular" human insulin.</string>
    <string name="insulin_hint1">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/SettingUpAaps/ConfigBuilder.html#insulin</string>
    <string name="sensitivity_label">Sensitivity Plugins</string>
    <string name="sensitivity_adjust">Sensitivity plugins allow AAPS to adjust for temporary or short-lived changes in insulin sensitivity (for example hormonal changes or issues with absorption at the infusion site).</string>
    <string name="sensitivity_edit">Sensitivity plugins provide the user with suggested changes to basal rates, I:C ratios, and ISF that can be used to edit profile.</string>
    <string name="sensitivity_cannula">Logging a cannula change will reset the Autosens ratio back to 100%.</string>
    <string name="sensitivity_time">Some of the plugin options have configurable time ranges and the user can set them.</string>
    <string name="sensitivity_hint1">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/DailyLifeWithAaps/SensitivityDetectionAndCob.html</string>
    <string name="sensitivity_hint2">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/DailyLifeWithAaps/KeyAapsFeatures.html#autosens</string>
    <string name="wrongcarbs_label">Carb Entry Errors</string>
    <string name="wrongcarbs_whattodo">What should you do if you’ve made an incorrect carb entry?</string>
    <string name="wrongcarbs_treatmentstab">Delete the incorrect entry in Treatments and enter the correct new carb value.</string>
    <string name="wrongcarbs_addinsulin">Bolus with insulin using the infusion set prime menu.</string>
    <string name="wrongcarbs_donothing">Do nothing – AAPS will make the appropriate adjustments.</string>
    <string name="wrongcarbs_bolus">Bolus with insulin using the Insulin (bolus) button in Overview.</string>
    <string name="wronginsulin_label">Insulin delivery/entry errors</string>
    <string name="wronginsulin_whattodo">What should you do if you received less insulin than the pump history suggests e.g. due to an occlusion, a failed cannula or forgetting to reattach the pump after a shower?</string>
    <string name="wronginsulin_careportal">Delete insulin data from Nightscout Careportal to remove it from the pump history.</string>
    <string name="wronginsulin_compare">Compare values in AAPS and pump history (if pump supports this).</string>
    <string name="wronginsulin_prime">Bolus a proportion of your calculated ‘missed’ insulin by either syringe/pen or using a prime.</string>
    <string name="cob_label">Carbs on Board (COB)</string>
    <string name="cob_question">How changing ISF value affects COB calculation by AAPS?</string>
    <string name="cob_longer">Increasing ISF will make the calculated carb absorption time longer</string>
    <string name="cob_shorter">Increasing ISF will make the calculated carb absorption time shorter</string>
    <string name="cob_no_effect">Increasing ISF will not affect calculated carbs absorption</string>
    <string name="cob2_question">How changing IC value affects COB calculation?</string>
    <string name="cob2_longer">Increasing IC will make the calculated carb absorption time longer</string>
    <string name="cob2_shorter">Increasing IC will make the calculated carb absorption time shorter</string>
    <string name="cob2_no_effect">Increasing IC will not affect calculated carbs absorption</string>
    <string name="cob3_question">How changing profile percentage affects COB calculation?</string>
    <string name="cob3_longer">Setting profile to 150% will make the calculated carb absorption time longer</string>
    <string name="cob3_shorter">Setting profile to 150% will make the calculated carb absorption time shorter</string>
    <string name="cob3_no_effect">Setting profile to 150% will not affect calculated carbs absorption</string>
    <string name="cob_hint1">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/DailyLifeWithAaps/CobCalculation.html</string>
    <string name="iob_value">IOB value is affected by issued temporary basals.</string>
    <string name="iob_hightemp">High temp basal will not be given when your blood sugar is below target.</string>
    <string name="iob_negiob">Negative IOB for a substantial period in the absence of exercise suggests your profile is too strong and less insulin is needed in your settings.</string>
    <string name="iob_posiob">Positive IOB for a substantial period suggests insulin resistance or unannounced meals.</string>
    <string name="breadgrams_label">Carb entry and boluses</string>
    <string name="breadgrams_grams">Only grams should be used for estimating and recording carbohydrates consumed.</string>
    <string name="breadgrams_exchange">Carbohydrates consumed can be recorded using an appropriate exchange system (e.g. DAFNE "CHO" exchanges or European "Bread Units").</string>
    <string name="breadgrams_decay">AAPS uses a dynamic model to estimate carb absorption and calculate COB.</string>
    <string name="breadgrams_calc">If blood glucose levels are outside acceptable values (too low or too high) the bolus calculator can be used to provide suggestions for carb or insulin corrections.</string>
    <string name="breadgrams_hint1">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/DailyLifeWithAaps/AapsScreens.html#bolus-wizard</string>
    <string name="breadgrams_hint2">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/SettingUpAaps/YourAapsProfile.html</string>
    <string name="extendedcarbs_label">e-carbs</string>
    <string name="extendedcarbs_handling">What could you use e-carbs (extended carbs) for?</string>
    <string name="extendedcarbs_future">To schedule carbs in the future, possibly distributed over an interval (similar to an extended bolus distributing insulin over an interval).</string>
    <string name="extendedcarbs_free">For logging \'free\' exercise carbs you want to hide from AAPS.</string>
    <string name="extendedcarbs_fat">e-carbs (distributed in the future) can assist AAPS in dealing with high fat/protein meals.</string>
    <string name="extendedcarbs_rescue">For logging rescue carbs you use to treat low blood glucose.</string>
    <string name="extendedcarbs_hint1">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/DailyLifeWithAaps/ExtendedCarbs.html</string>
    <string name="nsclient_label">Remote Monitoring</string>
    <string name="nsclient_howcanyou">How can you monitor AAPS (for example for your child) remotely?</string>
    <string name="nsclient_nightscout">AAPSClient app, Nightscout app and Nightscout webpage all allow you to follow AAPS remotely.</string>
    <string name="nsclient_dexcomfollow">Other apps (e.g. Dexcom follow, xDrip running in follow mode) allow you to follow some parameters (e.g. blood glucose/sensor values) remotely, but use different algorithms so may have inaccurate IOB or COB values.</string>
    <string name="nsclient_data">To follow AAPS remotely, both devices must have internet access (e.g. via Wi-Fi or mobile/cellular network data).</string>
    <string name="nsclient_fullcontrol">AAPSClient used as a remote follower will both monitor and provide full control of AAPS.</string>
    <string name="nsclient_hint1">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/RemoteFeatures/RemoteMonitoring.html</string>
    <string name="isf_label_exam">Insulin Sensitivity Factor (ISF)</string>
    <string name="isf_increasingvalue">Raising ISF values will lead to more insulin delivery to cover a specific amount of carbs.</string>
    <string name="isf_decreasingvalue">Reducing ISF values will lead to more insulin delivery to correct for an above target blood glucose.</string>
    <string name="isf_noeffect">Raising or lowering ISF does not affect insulin delivery when blood glucose levels are below target.</string>
    <string name="isf_preferences">ISF should be entered in your AAPS Preferences.</string>
    <string name="isf_hint1">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/SettingUpAaps/YourAapsProfile.html</string>
    <string name="ic_multiple">You can use more than one value for I:C ratio in your profile.</string>
    <string name="ic_isf">If you change your ISF in your profile you should always change your I:C ratio too.</string>
    <string name="ic_label_exam">Insulin to Carbohydrate Ratio (I:C ratio)</string>
    <string name="ic_increasingvalue">Higher I:C ratios lead to less insulin delivered for a given amount of carbs.</string>
    <string name="ic_decreasingvalue">Lower I:C ratios lead to less insulin delivered for a given amount of carbs.</string>
    <string name="ic_hint1">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/SettingUpAaps/YourAapsProfile.html</string>
    <string name="profileswitch_label">Profile Switching</string>
    <string name="profileswitch_pctwillchange">When specifying a 90% profile switch, which answers are true?</string>
    <string name="profileswitch_basallower">Basal rates will be 10% lower.</string>
    <string name="profileswitch_isfhigher">ISF will be 10% higher.</string>
    <string name="profileswitch_iclower">The value of the I:C ratio will be a 10% lower number.</string>
    <string name="profileswitch_unchanged">ISF and I:C ratios will be unchanged.</string>
    <string name="profileswitch_hint1" formatted="false">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/DailyLifeWithAaps/ProfileSwitch-ProfilePercentage.html</string>
    <string name="profileswitch2_label">Profile Switching</string>
    <string name="profileswitch2_pctwillchange">When specifying a 120% profile switch, which answers are true?</string>
    <string name="profileswitch2_bghigher">Target blood glucose will be 20% higher.</string>
    <string name="profileswitch2_basalhigher">Basal rates will be 20% higher.</string>
    <string name="profileswitch2_bgunchanged">Target blood glucose will be unchanged.</string>
    <string name="profileswitch2_isfhigher">ISF will be 20% higher.</string>
    <string name="profileswitchtime_label">Profile Switching</string>
    <string name="profileswitchtime_iwant">If you get up 2 hours earlier than usual, how should you notify AAPS of the change in your schedule?</string>
    <string name="profileswitchtime_2">Initiate a profile switch with a timeshift of 2</string>
    <string name="profileswitchtime__2">Initiate a profile switch with a timeshift of -2</string>
    <string name="profileswitchtime_tt">Set eating soon temporary target.</string>
    <string name="profileswitchtime_100">Do a profile switch to more than 100%.</string>
    <string name="profileswitchtime_hint1">https://wiki.aaps.app/en/latest/DailyLifeWithAaps/ProfileSwitch-ProfilePercentage.html</string>
    <string name="profileswitch4_label">Changes to profiles</string>
    <string name="profileswitch4_rates">Basal rates, ISF, I:C ratios, etc., should be set in profiles.</string>
    <string name="profileswitch4_internet">Activating changes to your Nightscout Profile requires your AAPS phone to have an internet connection.</string>
    <string name="profileswitch4_sufficient">Editing profiles to change values is sufficient to enact any changes made.</string>
    <string name="profileswitch4_multi">Multiple profiles can be set up and selected to accommodate changing circumstances (e.g., hormonal changes, shift working, weekdays/weekend lifestyle).</string>
    <string name="blank"></string>
    <string name="other_medication_label">Other Medication. Please read the statement below and check the box to accept the declaration.</string>
    <string name="other_medication_text">AAPS reduces basal rates or suspends insulin delivery to raise blood sugar. Drugs in the class SGLT2 inhibitors (gliflozins) can prevent increases in blood glucose and, thus, can produce a dangerous insulin deficiency leading to DKA.
\nCommon brand names are: Invokana®, Forxiga®, Jardiance®, Steglatro®, Suglat®, Apleway®, Deberza®, Synjardy®, Vokanamet®, Xigduo®.\n\nI hereby promise that I will not take such drugs when using AAPS or will deactivate the loop before using such drugs.</string>

</resources>

